Contact

amanda@amandapatern.com

www.linkedin.com/in/amandapate (LinkedIn) amandapatern.com (Personal)

Top Skills

Customer Service Management Teaching

Languages

Spanish (Limited Working)
English (Native or Bilingual)

Certifications

Registered Nurse Board Certified Registered Nurse

Honors-Awards

Transfer Scholarship for high GPA LaGrange College Scholarship Lagrange College Scholarship Transfer Scholarship for high GPA Research Scholar

Publications

Matters of the heart: Does the heart matter?

Heart disease is not only a mans disease.

Amanda Pate MSN, OCN, RN-BC

Travel Registered Nurse at O'Conner Greenville, Georgia

Summary

Currently working as a travel RN. Certified in Oncology and Medical Surgical. Daisy Award winner, March of Dimes Nurse of the Year finalist three years in a row, also AJC nurse of the year nominee many years in a row. Published author.

Experience

MedSource Travelers
Case Manager, Discharge Planning and Utilization Review
April 2019 - April 2020 (1 year 1 month)
San Jose, California

In this position I reviewed charts to ensure patients were in correct bed status while preparing reports for insurance and Medicare. Case management and discharge planning ensuring the patients received timely and appropriate care for the duration of stay. I also assisted the patient with being approved for skilled nursing and/or home health needs.

Emory Healthcare
Travel Registered Nurse
March 2018 - April 2019 (1 year 2 months)
Georgia

Worked on a busy medical surgical floor caring for patients in all degrees of illness.

Northside Hospital
Travel Registered Nurse
October 2017 - January 2018 (4 months)
Atlanta, Georgia

Travel RN on Oncology floor at Northside Hospital.

Meriwether County Firefighter Firefighter/Medical

June 2012 - December 2017 (5 years 7 months)

Meriwether County, Greenville, Georgia 30222

To provide emergency fire fighting, rescue and emergency medical care along with first aid to residents of the community.

Cancer Treatment Centers of America

Registered Onco-Cardiology Nurse/Chair for Education and Research Council

August 2014 - October 2017 (3 years 3 months)

Newnan, Ga.

My main focus was care management for our cardiology patients. Coordination with a multidisciplinary team as well as outside facilities in order to ensure high quality stress free care for our patients. Developing SWI along with policy writing. Performing literature searches to ensure highest quality care from the best evidence is being performed. When in the house supervisor role I am responsible for all floors from medsurg to ICU. Also responsible for supervising our urgent care unit, clinic, infusion and at times stepping in any roles needed to provide safe evidence based care to our patients. Responsible for placing patients in rooms providing safe staffing while collaborating with a multidisciplinary team. While charge I am responsible for two floors, medsurg and intermediate. While on the floor I am responsible for assessing the needs of the patient with a holistic approach on an ongoing basis, adjusting treatments based on multidisciplinary plan of care. Planning, delivering, directing, coordination and evaluation of therapeutic interventions based on the needs identified in the assessment process. Supervising of care delivered by unlicensed support staff. Providing the patient and family education in regards to the disease process, side effects of treatment and health promotion as well as supporting and reassurance. Ensuring an informed decision is being made regarding the patients therapeutic plan. Ensuring compliance with hospital policies and accrediting agencies.

LaGrange College

Clinical Instructor

September 2015 - December 2015 (4 months)

Part time clinical instructor for the Fall semester. Instructing nursing students on clinical practice and helping develop the skills needed to properly assess the patient and develop an effective care plan then implement the steps within the care plan in order to help the patient become healthier.

Piedmont Healthcare

Registered Nurse/Charge Nurse
July 2013 - October 2014 (1 year 4 months)

Newnan

In this position I was Charge/floor nurse. Taking 6-7 patients while charging which demonstrates my time management skills, as well as, staying calm under pressure. This was on an Ortho/Surgical/Medical floor. Responsible for providing nursing care to patients from birth through the lifecycle utilizing the nursing process in accordance with Piedmont Newnan Hospital's Mission, Values, and Vision Statement; functions within the framework of the policies and procedures of the organization and demonstrates professional growth and accountability. Guides and supervises nursing staff personnel, collaborates with other health care professionals and coordinates ancillary staff in the provision of quality nursing care. Blends compassion, caring and technologically appropriate competency resulting in holistic care to the patient. I am on a surgical medical floor taking care of longer term patients with specialized training in surgical care. Responsible for care of patients from admittance to before and after surgery until discharge. Also trained in medical surgical nursing. I have great attention to detail, patience and compassion for patients and the ability to work well within a team environment. Below is a copy of an article I wrote concerning heart disease, while working here at Piedmont, that Newnan Times Herald published. Please take a minute to read it and let me know what you think.

TroupCares
Nurse Volunteer
July 2012 - March 2014 (1 year 9 months)
Lagrange Georgia

All aspects of patient care that is currently needed such as blood pressure checks, patient education, patient counsel, working with other professionals in the healthcare field such as Doctors, Pharmacist, Nurses, Front Office Personnel.

LaGrange College Registered Nursing Student January 2010 - May 2013 (3 years 5 months) Lagrange College

I was a nursing student at Lagrange College and graduated in May with a BSN. Through the years, I have grown and developed additional skills to meet the needs of my patients and their families.

600 hours of clinical experience divided among: geriatrics, obstetrics, medicalsurgical, psychiatric, intensive care and community health.

Page 3 of 5

180 Hours of ICU experience.

Site locations include West Georgia Medical Center, Children's Healthcare of Atlanta at Scottish Rite and Egleston, Central State, Bradley Center, Florence Hand, Twin Fountains and Saint Francis.

Experience in Physical Assessment, Wound management, Safe medication preparation and administration, Perioperative Care and Mobility, Orthopedic/ Vascular Care, Antepartal Assessment, Mental Health, Intrapartal Assessment, Postpartal Assessment (Vaginal or C-Section), Newborn Assessment, IV therapy, oxygen therapy, cardiac monitoring, venipuncture, and patient teachin

Selective Designs
Office Manager
April 2009 - December 2009 (9 months)
Peachtree City, Georgia

Organized and coordinated office operations and procedures in order to ensure organizational effectiveness and efficiency

Reported directly to the president, supervised office staff, and maintained

office records which included bank deposits and bill paying
Maintained all office equipment and supplies, responsible for cutting office
costs by more than 75%

Kids R Kids Lead Teacher October 2007 - April 2009 (1 year 7 months) Peachtree City, Georgia

Instruct children in activities designed to promote social, physical, and intellectual growth needed for further development. Responsible for lesson plans and management of classroom and assistant teachers.

Heritage Home Improvement Inc Owner January 2001 - January 2007 (6 years 1 month) Newnan, Georgia 30263

Residential home improvement and construction business which was expanded into a profitable industrial, construction, and home improvement corporation

Handled property management, customer service, advertising, and corporate management

Ambling Management Company

Property Manager

April 2002 - April 2005 (3 years 1 month)

Responsible for all aspects of property management from collecting monies to evictions and advertisement.

DORCHESTER MANAGEMENT LTD

Property Manager

February 1998 - April 2002 (4 years 3 months)

Carrollton, Georgia

Managed property including budgeting, financials, remodeling, advertising.

Eastgate Apartments

Assistant Manager

July 1996 - February 1998 (1 year 8 months)

Newnan Ga

Assist manager with financials, budgeting, evictions, rental collections

Education

Capella University

Master's Degree, Nursing Management · (2014 - 2017)

LaGrange College

BSN, Registered Nursing · (2011 - 2013)

West Georgia Technical College

Core classes, Registered Nursing · (2010 - 2011)

Greenville High School 1993 High School

High School Diploma, General · (1990 - 1993)